# SANTIAGO CADAVID

#### **Biomedical Engineer**

@ santiago.cadavid94@gmail.com
 \$ 022 679 5579
 ■ 13 Huntly Ave, Grafton, 1023
 \$ https://cadavis8.github.io/
 in www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-cadavis

Auckland, New Zealand

### **PROFILE**

I am a biomedical engineer with experience measuring, acquiring and processing physiological human signals as well as controlling environmental variables in hospitals and clinical laboratories. I have a good understanding of a wide range of medical devices, electronics principles and medical concept which allow me to liaise between the clinical personnel and engineers making me an effective member in cross-functional teams. On top of my technical background, I have a general understanding of ICT management and digital transformation at a corporate level with emphasis on innovation and marketing due to my recent studies in technology management.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Assistant manager MK RD Limited

August 2018 - Currently

Auckland, NZ

# Field service engineer Iforware S.A.S.

# January 2017 - June 2017

- ♥ Medellín, Antioquia (Colombia)
- To design and create prototypes using open-source electronic prototyping platforms (i.e. Arduino) and commercial electronics.
- To operate with a variety of analog and digital transducers (temperature, humidity, dew point, gas concentration) for industrial and healthcare applications.
- To design and develop printed circuit boards (PCB) and assemble them.
- To develop hardware of traceability, telemetry and control.
- To support software tests in traceability, telemetry and control.
- To keep the correct operation of sensors and the telemetry system that were installed in hospitals and laboratories.

#### Research Fellow

#### Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano

- To evaluate different kinds of electrodes and their position configurations to improve the signal-noise ratio during surface electromyography (sEMG) signal acquisition.
- Acquisition of sEMG signals in healthy people during motor gestures involved during swallowing.
- To evaluate the activation patterns of each motor gesture performed.
- To prepare and carry out a workshop for students from different universities about electromyography and its applications.

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Open work Visa permit.
- NZ full driver license.

## **SKILLS**

Electrical/Electronics Science

Physics New enterprise development

Technology Marketing

Digital signal acquisition

Digital signal processing

Surface electromyography

Swallowing disorders

Academic and clinical research

Polygraph medical devices Mechanical ventilators Physical exam medical devices Laboratory medical devices



Microsoft Office MATLAB LabChart
LaTeX Arduino PCB design software

Curious A innate talent to teach

Innovative Approachable attitude

Commitment

# LANGUAGES

English Spanish



## **EDUCATION**

BSc(Eng) Biomedical Engineering Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano (ITM)

**2012 - 2017** 

Diploma level 7 in Technology Management Aspire2 International

Aspirez internat

**2017 - 2018** 

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Articles

- Cadavid-Arboleda, Santiago et al. (2017). "Assessment of Surface Electromyography During Orofacial Praxis in Healthy Subjects". In: VII Latin American Congress on Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia, October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 165–168. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Cantillo-Mackenzie, German et al. (2017). "Surface Electromyographic Characterization of Five Orofacial Ideomotor Praxis in 20 Healthy Individuals". In: VII Latin American Congress on Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia, October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 221–224. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Restrepo-Agudelo, Sebastian et al. (2017). "Improving surface EMG burst detection in infrahyoid muscles during swallowing using digital filters and discrete wavelet analysis". In: Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 35, pp. 1–8. ISSN: 10506411. DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2017.05.001. URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1050641116302991.

### REFERENCES

#### Eng. Juan David Arboleda

- @ Juan.Arboleda@foodstuffs.co.nz
- ➤ Foodstuffs North Island Limited +64 27 471 1439

#### Mgr. Metesh Keshav

- @ fortst@madmex.co.nz
- MK RD Limited +64 21 115 9692

#### Dr. Andrés Orozco Duque

- @ andresorozco@itm.edu.co
- Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano +57 (300) 682-8421